# Felipe Cardoso Moreira

Rio de Janeiro, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil



felipe.cardoso.rj@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/fellrock



+55 21 98587-5227



https://fellrock.github.io

## Summary

Since my collage research scholarship at 2011 I've been coding alongside some project. In 2020 was my launch as a professional IT in Accenture working as a Junior Data Engineer.

Just one year after I've became father and started to work as a Software Engineer at XP Inc. starting to have a bigger maturity and vision in the Tech Market. This work made me learn all about Microsoft development technologies (dotNET, C#, SQL, DevOps, Azure).

### **Experience**



#### Software Engineer

XP Inc.

Oct 2021 - Jan 2023 (1 year 4 months)

Main activity: Web development.

Responsability: Main area application update and maintenance developing pages, process and APIs.

Impact: Built 3 plataform pages that helped to reduce work hours of process in more than 70%.

Skills: ASP.NET, SQL Server, Bootstrap, DevOps, Javascript, SonarQube, Polaris, Integration and Unit Tests, Datadog, API data collection, .NET Core, Grafana, Postman.

# Junior Data Engineer

Accenture Brasil

Nov 2020 - Oct 2021 (1 year) Main activity: Data update.

Responsability: Maintain project datasets aided by international team throught manual and automatics update process that filtered and organize desire chunks of data.

Impact: The data collection made possible to elaborate complex machine learn theories that helped our client.

Skills: ETL, SQL Server, Power Bi, Pentaho Data Integration, Microsoft Power Automate, Python, Powershell, Power Query, Excel.



#### **Digital Systems Intern (IPqM)**

Marinha do Brasil

Mar 2017 - Sep 2017 (7 months)

Main activity: Embedded software development

Responsability: Plan, execute and maintain navy electronic projects.

Impact: Built periscope simulator that is been used to train new specialists on Brazilian Navy.

Skills: C# - Pascal - C - OrCad - AVR Microcontroller



#### Research Scholarship Holder (PIBIC)

**CNP**q

Sep 2011 - May 2014 (2 years 9 months) Main Activity: Software development

Responsability: Built a low-cost equipment to improve the experiments of the Physics lectures alongside with its own embedded software and application to make possible access data from computer.

Skills: Arduino - Pascal - Lazarus - Delphi - Circuits and Sensors.

#### **Education**

#### E Cefet/RJ

Bachelor of Engineering, Electrical and Electronics Engineering Jul 2009 - Dec 2017

Core Subjects: Electrical Circuits, Electronics, Digital Systems, Digital Electronic, Economy, Technology of Semiconductors, Technical Drawing, Calculus, Complex Variables, Strength of materials, Integrated Circuits.

#### Munster Technological University

Bachelor of Engineering, Electrical and Electronics Engineering 2014 - 2015

Core Subjects: Microcomputer Applications, Networks, Technological Entrepreneurship, IC Design, LabVIEW Visual Programming, Firmware Development, Digital System Design.

#### **Licenses & Certifications**

Clean Architecture Essencial - ASP .NET Core com C# - Udemy UC-e1690149-be38-474d-b1fd-06a6e6bb106d

- DevOps, CI/CD(Continuous Integration/Delivery for Beginners Udemy UC-2bcd6edf-e15d-4856-a963-6500f3d83bb7
- GIT and Visual Studio with Azure DevOps Repos for Developers Udemy UC-f39645a6-d5c7-47b8-af88-f67429032f65